这是二零二四年广西初中学业水平考试
英语科听力部分。
下面。
是听力试音时间。
Hi, Mark. I want to have a class party.
Will you help me?
Sure, Alice. So when shall we have the party?
What about Friday afternoon?
We won't have any lessons then.
Good idea. We can all meet and play party games.
Wonderful. I can play the dance music.
I will bring some flowers and paint some pictures for the party.
Nice. And we want different kinds of food.
You're right. We can ask Jackson and Lucy for help.
Okay. Let's start to get ready for the party.
No problem. Hi, Mark.
I want to have a class party.
Will you help me?
Sure, Alice. So when shall we have the party?
What about Friday afternoon?
We won't have any lessons then.
Good idea. We can all meet and play party games.
Wonderful. I can play the dance music.
I will bring some flowers and paint some pictures for the party.
Nice. And we want different kinds of food.
You're right. We can ask Jackson and Lucy for help.
Okay. Let's start to get ready for the party.
No problem. This now.
因到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
一听力一听句子，选图片。
你将听到五个句子，请选出与所听句子内容相符的图片。
有一幅图是多余的。
每。
一个句子读两遍。
1. His uncle is a doctor.
2. You can see three apples in the basket.
3. The man is running on the road.
4. There is a computer on the
There is a computer on the desk.
4. There 5.
My family had a picnic in the park yesterday.
5. My family had a in the park yesterday.
二，听短对话，选择最佳答案。
你将听到五段对话，每段对话后有
is Please choose conversation content.
一个小题，请根据。
对话内容，选出最佳答案。
每段对话读两遍。
6. Tony, what's your favorite animal?
Tony, what's Tony, what's your favorite animal?
7. I think dogs are lovely.
7. Dad, how is the weather today?
It's sunny. Let's take a walk on such a sunny day.
8. Good morning, What would you like to drink, tea or coffee?
Coffee or Coffee, please.
Good morning, What would you like to drink, tea or coffee?
Coffee, please. 9.
Excuse me, can you tell me the way to the hospital?
Yes. Go along the street and you can find it at the end of the street.
9. Excuse me, Can you tell me the way to the hospital?
10. Cindy, would you like to watch the football match with me?
Well, it's not my cup of tea, but my brother, Tom, is crazy about it.
10. Mike, do you have any plans for this weekend?
三听长对话，选择最佳答案。
你将听到三段对话，请根据对话内容
选出每。
每个问题的最佳答案，
每段对话读两遍。
请听第一段对话，回答第十一至十三小题。
Yes, I'm going to the zoo.
Who will go with you?
My brother. How will you go there?
By bus. What about you, Alice?
A new movie is on.
I'm going to watch the movie.
Have a good time.
Mike, do you have any plans for this weekend?
Yes, I'm going to the zoo.
will go with you?
My brother. How will you go there?
By bus. What about you, Alice?
A new movie is on.
I'm going to watch the movie.
Have a good time.
Please David, where did you go yesterday?
请听第二段对话，回答
第十四至十六小题。
I went to the old people's home with my classmates.
What did you do there?
Some old people cannot do cleaning.
I did some cleaning for them.
Great. I want to join you.
We will go there again next Sunday.
You can join us.
Good idea. Where shall we meet next Sunday?
At the school gate at 9 a.m.
Okay. See you at the school gate then.
David, where did you go yesterday?
I went to the old people's home with my classmates.
What did you do there?
Some old people cannot do cleaning.
I did some cleaning for them.
Great. I want to join you.
We will go there again next Sunday.
You can join us.
Good idea. Where shall we meet next Sunday?
At the school gate at 9 a.m.
Okay. See you at the school gate then.
请听第三段对话，回答第十七至二十小题
Jack, it's time for dinner.
I'm coming, What are you doing?
I'm writing a card.
The card is for my new friend.
Who is your new friend?
My new friend is Peter.
What is Peter like?
He is kind.
He is kind to everyone.
What is his hobby?
His hobby is swimming.
He often goes swimming with his father.
Your card will make him happy.
I hope so.
Jack, it's time for dinner.
I'm coming, mom.
What are you doing?
I'm writing a card.
The card is for my new friend.
Who is your new friend?
My new friend is Peter.
What is Peter like?
He is kind.
He is kind to everyone.
What is his hobby?
His hobby is swimming.
He often goes swimming with his father.
Your card will make him happy.
I hope so.
What Hello, I'm Linda.
四，听短文，选择最佳答案。
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容
选出每个问题的最佳答案。
短文读两遍。
I come from Canada.
I'm very happy to share my experience in Beijing.
I came to study in Beijing three months ago.
At the beginning, I felt lonely because I had no friends in this city.
And I had difficulty with my study.
When I felt lonely, I missed my old friends in Canada very much.
Luckily, my teachers and classmates here are friendly to me.
My teachers always help me with my study.
With their help, I have made great progress.
Sometimes, my classmates show me around Beijing.
They took me to visit the Great Wall last Saturday.
We took many photos of the Great Wall.
Now I have fallen in love with the life in Beijing.
Hello, I'm Linda.
I come from Canada.
I'm very happy to share my experience in Beijing.
I came to study in Beijing three months ago.
At the beginning, I felt lonely because I had no friends in this city.
And I had difficulty with my study.
When I felt lonely, I missed my old friends in Canada very much.
Luckily, my teachers and classmates here are friendly to me.
My teachers always help me with my study.
With their help, I have made great progress.
Sometimes, my classmates show me around Beijing.
They took me to visit the Great Wall last Saturday.
We took many photos of the Great Wall.
Now I have fallen in love with the life in Beijing.
五，听短文填信息。
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容，将所缺信息填入答题卡对应的横线
上，每空一词。
短文读三遍。
Good afternoon, everybody.
I am going to introduce the activities in our school clubs.
Students of each grade can join the clubs.
Our clubs are open from 5 p.m.
to 6 p.m.
on weekdays. Here are the clubs for you to choose from.
In the nature club, you can discover the wonder of nature.
In the food and drink club, you can learn to make biscuits and dumplings.
The reading club is the best choice for poem lovers.
You can know about Morden poems in the club.
This term, an English teacher from England, will help you to develop your speaking
skills. So in the English club, you can learn how to pronounce words correctly with
his help. Welcome to join us.
Good afternoon, everybody.
I am going to introduce the activities in our school clubs.
Students of each grade can join the clubs.
Our clubs are open from 5 p.m.
to 6 p.m.
on weekdays. Here are the clubs for you to choose from.
In the nature club, you can discover the wonder of nature.
In the food and drink club, you can learn to make biscuits and dumplings.
The reading club is the best choice for poem lovers.
You can know about Morden poems in the club.
This term, an English teacher from England, will help you to develop your speaking
skills. So in the English club, you can learn how to pronounce words correctly with
his help. Welcome to join us.
Good afternoon, everybody.
I am going to introduce the activities in our school clubs.
Students of each grade can join the clubs.
Our clubs are open from 5 p.m.
to 6 p.m.
on weekdays. Here are the clubs for you to choose from.
In the nature club, you can discover the wonder of nature.
In the food and drink club, you can learn to make biscuits and dumplings.
The reading club is the best choice for poem lovers.
You can know about Morden poems in the club.
This term, an English teacher from England, will help you to develop your speaking
skills. So in the English club, you can learn how to pronounce words correctly with
his help. Welcome to join us.
听力测试结束。
Thank you.